# **Harpreet Singh**

Email: harpreetsinghjp888@gmail.com

Phone: +64-021 0260 4586

# **Senior Software Developer**

With 10 years of experience as a software developer, I am a seasoned professional known for my agile and collaborative approach. I have a proven ability to quickly grasp new technologies and a relentless passion for learning. My high level of productivity and adaptability make me an asset to any team. In addition, I have a knack for mentoring others and possess strong technical skills.

## Skills

### **Front-End Web Development**

AngularJS, ReactJS, Typescript, NestJS WebSocket, Service Worker Bootstrap, CSS3, HTML5

#### **Cloud Service**

Amazon Web Services(AWS) Microsoft Azure

### **Additional Strength**

Github Actions, MochaJS Jasmine, Karma, WebDriverIO GruntJS, Webpack GIT, Kanbanize

# Back-End Web Development Node IS with Mongo DB. Dv

NodeJS with MongoDB, DynamoDB PHP(Symfony2) with MySQL RESTful APIs, Swagger

#### **Microservices & RestAPIs**

Event Driven Architecture
API Development, Integration, Security
API Testing

#### CI/CD

Github Actions Codeship, Heroku Jenkins

Currently learning following framework/tool:

React, React native Dart, Flutter

# **Experience**

### Senior Analyst Programmer – ANZ Bank

May 2023 to present

Currently working as a Senior Analyst Programmer.

Skills: NodeJS, Ember, AWS, Typescript, RESTful APIs

- Security and Architecture Management: Proactively ensure the security and integrity of the
  application by implementing robust security measures and adhering to industry best
  practices. Responsible for designing and maintaining the application's architecture, ensuring
  scalability, performance, and maintainability.
- **Developer Mentoring:** Actively mentor junior developers, providing guidance and support in their professional growth. Share valuable knowledge, conduct comprehensive code reviews, and foster a collaborative learning environment to enhance the technical skills of the team.

#### Software Developer - Author-it

March 2022 to May 2023

I have worked on a product from ASC called Docuvera. Docuvera is a cloud-based Component Content Management System for the creation, management, translation, localization & publishing of technical documentation, compliance & procedures, HR documents and eLearning solutions.

**Skills:** NodeJS, NestJS, NX, DynamoDb, AngularJS, Typescript, RESTful APIs, Amazon Web Services(AWS), Mocha, Gitlab

- **NX upgrade:** Worked on integrating NX to various microservices.
- APIs: Worked on the framework to write API tests by mocking various microservices.
- Event Driven Architecture: Worked on implement an event driven architecture for change logs

Full Stack Developer – The Open Polytechnic of New Zealand August 2016 to February 2022 iQualify(www.iqualify.com) which is an eLearning platform.

**Skills:** NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB, Firebase, AngularJS, Typescript, Websockets, RESTful APIs, Microsoft Azure, MochaJS, WebdriverIO, Jasmine, WebpackJS, Codeship, Heroku, GIT, Bootstrap, NestJS, NX

- Integrating APIs: I have worked on integrating Learnosity(www.learnosity.com) APIs into our system to revamp quizzes, assessments and activities.
- **Microsoft Azure:** In our platform we use Microsoft Azure as a cloud-based service. I have worked on implementing Azure Function for search in our app.
- **Refactoring to Angular:** Refactored a big part of our app from AngularJS(v1.7) to Angular(v5.1).
- **Mentoring:** Mentoring new team members to come on-board and get a head start with Learnosity APIs.

### Software Developer – Website Travel Pvt. Ltd (<u>www.websitetravel.com</u>) July 2013 to August 2016

Website travel comprises Travel Desk Management System (TDMS) and Content Management System (CMS). Suppliers add products through CMS and Agents sell these products through TDMS to various customers.

**Skills:** Symfony2, PHP, MySQL, BackboneJS, RESTful APIs, Smarty, UnderscoreJS, Kanbanize, PHPUnit, JSUnit, Jenkins, Bootstrap, SASS, GIT, Bootstrap.

- Supplier & Agent API: I have worked on adding functionality for better error handling around API orders, support live availability products from Junction6 API, add & support pickup locations.
- **Virgin Flight API:** I worked on a module in which we need to apply an agent commission percentage after getting fares from Virgin API and display the updated fares for agents.

### PHP Developer - Goo2o Technologies & KritiSolutions

Oct 2010 to Feb 2012

In this company I have worked on an in-house website www.goo2o.com.

- Framework: Used PHP (Zend Framework), MySQL and jQuery for coding.
- Other: Integration of dispute management and order module and Location management.

## **Education**

Postgraduate Diploma in Computer Science (PGDip)	2012-2013
University of Waikato, New Zealand	
Bachelor of Engineering (Information Technology)	2006-2010
Maharishi Dayanand University, India	

# **Other Experience**

Volunteer – Commonwealth Games, India	2010
Volunteer – Gallagher Great Race, Hamilton	2012
Participated in 49 <sup>th</sup> Senior National Ball-Badminton Championship	2007

# **Hobbies**

Snowboarding, Climbing, Hiking, Travelling, Rubik's Cube.

## References

Available on request.